# Saran .A

Software Developer

### Personal Details



+1 513 488-3856



Saran1209@gmail.com



8 Sherman Place, Utica, NY - 13502



linkedin.com/in/saran allam

#### **Technical Skills**

- Python
- **Jscript**
- (
- SQL
- C++
- GIT
- JAVA
- Flask
- HTML
- Django
- CSS

#### **Achievements**

- 1st Prize in a Robotics
   Competition Organized by
   Robo Edutech India Pvt.Ltd.
- 1<sup>st</sup> Prize in a National Level Student Project, Paper and Poster Presentation Competition.
- 3<sup>rd</sup> Prize in a State level
   Robotics Competition
   Organized by Robo Edutech
   India Pvt.Ltd.
- Volunteered at the 5<sup>th</sup>
   International conference on "Innovations in Electronics
   & Communication
   Engineering (ICIECE-2016)".
- 5. Elected as the Student leader for Robotics lab at GNI institutions.

## **Professional Summary**

Passionate Software Developer with 2+ years of Experience in Python, Java, C++ on IDE — Sublime editor, Jupyter, PyCharm, Visual studio, Eclipse. Well versed with Data structure and algorithms. Experienced in developing Web-based application using Python, Flask and Django Web framework. Experience with several python packages like NumPy, Matplotlib, Beautiful Soup, Pandas data frame.

## **Experience**

SUNY Poly, Utica, NY

(09/2018-05/2020)

**Graduate Teaching Assistant** 

- Assisted Students in Programming (Python & Java)
- Assisted Students in Object Oriented Programming course work.
- Supported the class lecture and Presentations of the course work.
- Worked on Research work related to AI and Machine learning.
- Observed Professor in Lecture and best Practices.

Concentrix Daksh Services India (10/2017-08/2018)
Private Limited.

**Transaction Analyst** 

- Supported Client with mitigating and monitoring user alerts and reports.
- Collaborated with law enforcement officials to track flagged reports.

## **Academic Projects**

- 1. Developed a Web application using **Flask** and Implemented **Natural Language Processing** Chat bot with a **Web Scrappe**r to extract information.
- 2. Heart Disease Prediction using **Machine Learning** algorithms like **KNN**, **Decision Tree**, **Random Forest**.
- 3. Programmed and built a Prototype of a **Steering less vehicle** for **physically Handicapped** person.
- 4. Built and Programmed a Stair climbing robot based on MARS Rover.

#### **Education**

SUNY Poly, Utica, NY (08/2018-07/2020) Master of Science in Computer Information Science GPA – 3.4

GNITC, HYDERABAD, TELANGANA INDIA (2013-2017)

Bachelor of Technology in Mechanical Engineering

keywords: Python, Django, Unix, XML, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, MySQL, SQLite, Python Libraries, git.